# CURRICUI UM VITAF

Mr Adam Bryan 103 Cemetery Road, Cannock, Staffordshire. WS11 5QG.

**☎**: 07929 625353 **☎**: adam181189@gmail.com

Full UK driving Licence

Experienced Primary School Teacher, with an enthusiasm and passion for teaching in Early Years. Understands the importance of inspiring play experiences for young children to develop independent learning. Enjoys leading a team of passionate practitioners, giving support and sharing knowledge, ensuring children progress. Highly experienced with children who speak English as an additional language.

## **Teaching Experience**

### May 2019 to Present - Connex Education (Supply teacher)

- Attend school bookings in good time, ensuring flexibility.
- Encourage positive behaviour with use of positive re-enforcement, adhering to the behaviour policy.
- Ensuring positive working relationships at all times with regular staff.
- Marking any work and writing observations which the regular teacher may find useful.

### Jan 2018 to April 2019 - Bloxwich Academy

- Taught in a 52 place Nursery.
- Collecting evidence through paper learning journals.
- Working with outside agencies (such as social workers, speech and language specialists, play workers) to ensure children with difficult background were supported.
- Read Write Inc training, including RWI in Nursery training.

# Jan 2016 to Dec 2017 - Grestone Academy

- Worked alongside the head teacher and deputy head to set up a brand-new Nursery in this school.
- Purchasing resources and setting up an effective learning environment.
- Directed a small team of two TAs. Supported staff with writing observations and deciding next steps for learning.
- Majority EAL children.
- Assessed children and analysed the data, ensuring high expectations at all times.

# Sep 2014 to Dec 2015 - Jerome Primary School

- Began as a Newly-Qualified Teacher in this "Good" Primary School.
- Taught Nursery part time, mornings only.
- Made use of the planning, assessment cycle to ensure children were progressing, and shared knowledge with parents as required.
- Applying knowledge of the EYFS (22-36 months, 30-50 months and 40-60 months).
- Effectively made use of the 2simple program for learning journals.

### May 2013 to Jul 2014 - Timbertree Primary School

- Worked within part of a foundation stage unit.
- Worked primarily as a Teaching Assistant.
- Covered PPA in EYFS.
- Planned for outdoor learning-forest school area.
- Observation, assessing, following up next steps, adult led activities.
- Nursery and Reception.

# Jan 2013 to May 2013 - St James CofE Primary School

- Worked as part of a foundation stage team.
- Part of a Job share, collaborating with the other teacher by sharing assessments and working together to plan and prepare lessons.
- Observing and assessing, following up next steps, collating evidence.
- Displays and working walls.

# **Other work Experience**

## Oct 2008 to Oct 2011 - Customer Service Assistant at Screwfix Direct (Aston)

- Part time position alongside my degree study.
- Serving customers on till.
- Making use of mathematic skills.
- Having a friendly and approachable disposition with customers.
- Make sales of additional order value products with customers.
- Warehouse work, scanning and collecting items from the back of the store.

# Qualifications

Subject	Qualification	Address of institution	Date
PGCE Early Years	PGCE (QTS)	University College Birmingham	07/2012
Early Childhood Education Studies	BA (Hons)	Birmingham City University	06/2011
Religious Education, English Literature,	A-Levels	Brownhills CTC, Walsall, West Midlands	08/2008

#### Interests

During my spare time I have a wide variety of interests. They include reading, listening to audiobooks, writing, playing piano, swimming, visiting museums, travel, and coding (HTML, CSS and Javascript, with C# in unity). I also enjoy listening to a wide variety of music.

# References

### Available on request